(カグヤ)お前たちが… 憎い。
I…
detest you.
ハゴロモ ハムラ。
Hagoromo…
Hamura…
お前たちは わらわのもの！
You…
are mine.
(ゼツ)俺の役目は終わりだ。
My role has come to an end.
You shall return with me to
the almighty god that is Mother.
(ゼツ)俺と一緒に
母なる全能の神へと戻るのだ。
(ナルト)だけが…。
You two aren't…
お前らだけが→
You two alone aren't the entirety
of shinobi history!
忍の歴史じゃねえんだよ！
それに 親離れを喜ぶのが→
Besides…
moms are supposed to be happy
about their kids leaving the nest!
母ちゃんってもんだろうが。
That's what being a mom means!
(ゼツ)反抗期が長いな。
Your teenage rebellion continues.
(ゼツ)母は チャクラの祖 そのもの。
Mother is the very progenitor of chakra.
(ゼツ)お前ら ガキが何をしてもムダだ。
You brats can't hope to
accomplish anything.
(サスケ)封印の術を発動する
隙を作る必要はあるぞ ナルト。
Naruto, we need to make an opening,
so we can launch the Sealing Jutsu.
ああ！ もうあれしかねえ
あの術しか。
Yeah!
And the only thing that will work…
is that jutsu!
The No. 1 Most Unpredictable Ninja
あの術？
"That" jutsu?
Yeah…
ああ サスケ ちょっと耳貸せ。
Sasuke, hear me out.
何を企んでいるかは知らんが→
I don't know what you're scheming,
but Mother absorbs all jutsu.
母は すべての術を 吸収する。
Your actions are meaningless.
お前らの行為は 無意味だぞ。
(カカシ)どうだ？
How is it going?
(サクラ)今は にらみ合ってるみたい。
Looks like they're just staring
each other down.
(カカシ)そうか。
I see…
《カカシ : 幻術でもない この空間に
強制的に引きずり込む力…》
The power to forcefully drag us all
into this dimension,
that isn't genjutsu…
次元が違いすぎる。
This is on a totally different scale.
あれはまるで… 神だ。
She's like…
…a god.
あんなやつと
どう戦うつもりなの？ ナルト。
How do you plan on fighting
someone like that, Naruto?
これで最後かもしんねえけど→
This could be the end…
やるだけやってみねえとな。
But we gotta give it our best shot.
今までだって
それの連続だったろ。
Just like we've been
doing all along, right?
(オビト)うっ…。
お前 本気か？
Are you serious?
We won't know unless we try.
やってみるまでわかんねえだろ。
I've been secretly
practicing this jutsu
俺ってば ひそかに螺旋丸以上に→
even more than the Rasengan,
ya know?!
この術を
練習してきたんだってばよ。
やってみる価値はあんだろが。
It's worth giving it a shot, right?
それで やつの隙が
できる可能性があるなら。
If there's a chance
it'll create an opening…
いいだろう 俺も
左目の準備をしておく。
Fine. I'll get my left eye ready.
いくぞ。
おう。
Let's do it!
Yeah!
《天照！》
Amaterasu!
動いた。
They're making a move!
くらえ。
Take this!
おいろけ…。
(みんな)逆ハーレムの術。
Sexy Jutsu:
- Reverse Harem Jutsu!
《おいろけ系は
強いやつほど→
Sexy-type jutsu tend to work better
on stronger opponents, ya know!
よく効く傾向に
あるんだってばよ》
《アホ！ この状況で
なんて術してんのよ！
That idiot! Using a jutsu like that
in this situation?!
That might work on me,
but there's no way that jutsu
私は別として そんな術が
あんな神みたいなのに効くか！》
will work on someone so god-like!
《効いた～！》
It worked?!
《チャクラの祖だか
何だか知らねえが➡
You may be the progenitor
of chakra or whatever…
But I'll bet you've never seen
a jutsu like this!
見たことねえだろ こんな術！》
これが忍の歴史だ この野郎！
This is the history of shinobi, ya fool!
《意外性ナンバーワン。
The number one most unpredictable…
まさか ナルトのこのエロ忍術が
世界を救うことになるのか？》
Don't tell me that
Naruto's Pervy Ninjutsu
is going to save the world!
((自来也 : 世界を救う予言の子は
ナルトだと ワシは信じとる。
I believe that Naruto is
the Child of Prophecy
who will save the world.
木ノ葉の忍の道で言うならば
隔世遺伝とでも言うのかのう。
Perhaps he's a throwback to another age
in the Leaf's Shinobi Way.
(ミナトより ワシに似て
かわいいところがあってのう))
He's more like me than Minato,
and he can be very endearing.
《見てますか 自来也先生！》
Master Jiraiya, are you watching?!
今だ ナルト！
おう！
Now, Naruto!
Right!
うお～！
はあ～！
《冷てえ！ なんだ!?》
《氷!?》
It's cold! What's going on?!
Ice?
変わった？
It changed!
この場所
また移動したのか？
This place…
Did we shift dimensions again?
これ どっちの術の効果なの？
ナルト。
Whose jutsu effects are
we seeing, Naruto?
え えっと これは たぶん…。
Huh?!
Uh, this is probably…
It feels the same as the time
we were taken
前回の溶岩の世界に
行ったときと同じ感じだ。
to that previous lava world.
おそらく敵の能力に違いない。
There's no mistake that
this is our enemy's ability.
(カカシ)一瞬で世界を書き変え
それが実体であること。
To be able to rewrite the world
in an instant and make it reality…
まるで 幻術だよ これこそ。
This really is just like genjutsu.
今度は氷の世界
どういう原理？
An ice world this time?!
On what principle?
《消えやがった！》
She vanished!
This ability…
《この能力
空間を移動するのか》
Can she move across dimensions?
この…！
Why that—!
《天照！》
Amaterasu!
《加具土命》
Flame Control!
サンキュー。
Thanks, Sasuke!
サスケ すまねえ。
Sorry the Sexy Jutsu didn't work.
おいろけは
失敗しちまった。
フン あんな術で倒せるとは
ハナから思ってない。
I never really expected that
kind of jutsu would work.
今度は俺の作戦でいく
協力しろ。
This time, we're going
with my strategy…
Help me out.
母さん こいつら厄介だね。
Mother… These two
are quite annoying.
もうさ こいつら分けちまえば？
Why don't you split them
up already…
そして １匹ずつ…。
and take them on separately?
うっ。
あっ。
ぐっ！
ここは？
Where am I?
サスケ！
Sasuke!
くっ… うぅ…。
クソッ！
Damn it!
これでもう
母さんを封印できない。
Now you won't be able to
seal Mother away.
まずは お前のチャクラを
すべて吸い尽くす。
First, I'll suck out all
of your chakra!
(ゼツ)いい反射神経だ。
You have nice reflexes.
とにかく サスケを見つけねえと。
First, I have to find Sasuke!
(ゼツ)速いね この子。
This child is fast.
どっから来るか
わかんねえってことか。
So I guess I won't be able to tell
where she's gonna strike from…
何だ!?
What is that?
もしかしたら→
Is it possible that…
私たちだけ この世界に
連れてこられたのかも。
we're the only ones
who were brought to this world?
いや 本体の俺は
この世界にいるってばよ。
No. The real me is here too.
ただ サスケは感知できねえ。
But I can't sense Sasuke.
(オビト)うっ…。
どこだ？
オビト。
Where am I?
Obito!
カカシか。
Is that you, Kakashi?
俺は 死んだはず。
I thought I died…
俺が回復させた。
ナルト。
I healed you.
Naruto!
でも…。
But…
ハァ… あぁ わかっている。
Yeah…
I know.
マダラは どうなった？ 倒したのか？
What happened to Madara?
Did you take him down?
いや そうじゃなくなった。
No, things ended up
a little differently.
俺が簡単に説明すっから。
I'll explain it simply.
ついでに みんなにも
六道仙人やカグヤのこと→
Might as well tell you guys
about The Sage of the Six Paths
and Kaguya too, and that seal!
その封印のことも。
何があったかわからないが
まだ敵は倒してはいないんだな？
I don't know what happened,
but I assume you didn't defeat
the enemy yet?
なら そこへ俺を連れていけ。
Take me to where the fight is.
その間に話を聞く。
You can tell me on the way.
サスケは感知できねえし
本体がピリピリしてんのもわかる。
I can't sense Sasuke…
And my real body feels tingly.
向こうは危ねえかもしんねえぞ。
It might be real dangerous
over there!
私たちが 足手まといか→
I don't know if we'll be helpful
or in the way.
役に立てるかどうかは
わからない。
けど 役に立てるときに
そこにいないで➡
But I don't want
to fail because
we weren't there
when we were needed.
失敗したくないの。
どうせ そのカグヤってのを
倒さないことには→
Besides, if we don't bring down
this Kaguya,
our world is done for.
俺たちの世界も終わりだ。
残ってる俺たちだけで
あがいてみるしかないんだ。
The few of us who are left have
to do whatever we can…
もう とっくに
覚悟は決まってただろ。
We had our minds made up
from the very start, right?
(カカシ)死ぬ覚悟は。
That we're all ready to die.
ハァ ハァ…。
何をしてもダメか。
Nothing seems to work…
It's hard to believe.
(オビト)信じられんが とにかく
そのカグヤってのを封印するには→
So both your powers and
Sasuke's are necessary
ナルトとサスケの２人の力が
必要ってことだな。
in order to seal away this Kaguya?
ああ。 でも さっきも言ったけど
サスケが感知できねえんだ。
Yeah!
But like I said earlier,
I can't sense Sasuke at all!
氷が… 動いてるな。
The ice…is moving.
あそこだ！
Over there!
グッ！
《クッ 自然と一体化してやがる》
She's merged with Nature!
カハッ！
ナルト！
Naruto!
やっと出てきやがったな。
She's finally showing herself.
どうなってんの？ あれ…。
What's happening?
《時空間の類だな》
That's a form of Time-Space.
クッ！
クソッ。 ダメだ。
Damn it! It's no good!
《よし 縛られたフリはできた。
Okay… I've made it look
like I'm restrained…
あとは やつが近づいてきたときを
狙うってばよ》
I'll just wait until she gets closer!
サスケは急に感知できなくなった
と言ったな。
You said you suddenly
stopped sensing Sasuke?
おう。
Yeah.
I suspect he was taken
to another dimension.
なら 別空間へ飛ばされたと
想像できる。
やつは
時空間から出てきやがった。
She emerged from
a different Time-Space.
俺の瞳術と よく似た能力だ。
It's similar to
my own Visual Prowess.
入れるか？
Can you enter it?
もう一度
やつが空間をつなげ→
If I resonate my Kamui
開いたと同時に
俺の神威と共鳴させれば→
the next time she connects and opens
a portal to another Time-Space,
まず間違いなく入り込める。
I'm positive I can enter it.
そこに サスケがいれば➡
If Sasuke is there, I can bring him back
to this dimension.
こっちに
連れて帰ってくることはできる。
よっしゃ。 なら俺は
本体のサポートに回っから。
All right!
Then I'll go and support
the real me.
ただ…。
However…
それには膨大なチャクラがいる。
I'll need an enormous amount
of chakra to do it…
俺の時空間じゃないからな。
since it's not
my own Time-Space.
If my chakra runs out
while I'm there, I'm done.
向こうで
チャクラが切れたら終わりだ。
なら 俺も行く。
Then I'll go with you.
The real me won't go down
that quickly.
本体も すぐに
やられたりはしねえ。
俺は 強えから。
Because I'm strong.
Your Clone Chakra isn't enough.
分身のお前のチャクラでも足りない。
私の百豪のチャクラがあっても
足りませんか？
Would it still be inadequate with
my 100 Healings Chakra?
それで 限度いっぱいだ。
That would give me
the bare minimum.
２人とも 俺と来い！
はい！
Both of you, come with me.
All right!
サスケが その空間に
いるかどうかもわからない。
We don't even know if
Sasuke is in that Time-Space.
But we'll start by getting
into close range with her.
だが まずは やつの懐に入り➡
サスケは 必ず 俺が見つけ
お前の本体まで届ける。
I promise to find Sasuke,
and deliver him to the real you.
オビト… 俺のことを助けてくれて
ありがとう。
Obito.
Thanks for rescuing me…
そして サスケまで…。
And Sasuke too.
フン…。
Don't thank someone like me.
こんな俺に 礼など言うな。
敵を見てろ。
Just keep an eye on the enemy.
So no more masks, huh?
もう 面はねえんだな。
俺は カカシの友であり
お前の父の部下であり→
I'm…Kakashi's friend,
your father's subordinate,
サスケと同じ うちはであり
そして…。
I'm an Uchiha just like Sasuke…
and…
((火影ってのは
痛えの我慢して→
The Hokage is someone
who endures pain
and takes the lead
in front of everyone…
みんなの前を
歩いてるやつのことだ。
There is no shortcut to
becoming the Hokage!
火影になるやつに近道はねえし➡
There are no ways out for the one
who becomes the Hokage!
(なったやつに逃げ道はねえよ！))
((そして あいつの
そういう歩き方が→
The way he forges ahead
draws others towards him.
仲間を引き寄せる。
(つまずきそうなら 助けたくなる))
He makes you want to reach out
when he's about to stumble.
I…
(オビト)俺は
お前と同じ夢をみた先輩だった。
I am your senior who dreamt
the same dream as you.
時間のない俺が 今さら
詭弁を垂れるつもりはない。
I'm not going to waste time
on a speech,
because I'm almost out of time.
But…I just ask that you
let me walk in front of you…
ただ せめて
お前たちの前を歩いて…。
死なせてくれ。
and die for you.
(ミナト)遅くなりました。
何か わかりましたか？
I'm sorry I'm late.
Have you learned anything yet?
There's no one here.
(柱間)誰も おらぬ。
ただ マダラの下半身があるだけぞ。
Just the lower half of Madara's body.
(ミナト)マダラの半身が
転がっているなら→
Does finding Madara's lower half mean
that we should
consider him dead?
マダラは死んだものと考えて
いいのでしょうか？
I have a bad feeling about this…
嫌な予感もしますが…。
(扉間)どちらにしろ
やつの無限月読とやらは→
Either way, it seems he completed
his Infinite Tsukuyomi.
完成してしまったようだな。
And apparently,
it doesn't affect us dead…
死者の我らは かからぬようだが。
四代目…
そっちは どうだったのだ？
How did things go on your end,
Fourth Hokage?
術にかかった人々を
解放しようと→
I cut part of the tree
to try to free the people
entrapped in the jutsu,
みんなを包む木を切って
救出を試みましたが→
誰１人 目覚めることは
ありませんでした。
but they didn't awaken.
しかも すぐに 次の木のツタが
絡み取ってしまうんです。
(ヒルゼン)やはり 同じか。
マダラの生死を確認しつつ
ことを知るなら➡
その下半身を使い→
マダラを穢土転生してみれば
はっきりする。
そして 吐かせる。
それには
別の生け贄がいるではないか！
ここに来て そんな甘いことを！
何か 別の方法で…。
やはり お前は優しいやつよ。
アシュラの前任者よ。
あなたは？
名を ハゴロモ。
忍宗の開祖にして
六道仙人ともいう。